<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mediumish</title>
    <description>Chelsea's 14-month Data Science Journey at Asian Institute of Management</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 16:45:48 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 16:45:48 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Uncovering Similarities between recipes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subject/s of Focus: Data Mining and Wrangling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authors: Gilbert Chua, Chelsea Ong, Jomilynn Rebanal, Van Yu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This project is for the fulfillment of the requirements in our Data Mining and Wrangling course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;executive-summary&quot;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recipes are the blueprint for a dish and changes in the ingredients may either enrich or worsen the taste. Recipe tweaking due to the unavailability of certain ingredients is a common dilemma among home cooks and restauranteurs. In this study, the researchers explored more than 38,000 recipes scraped from allrecipes.com to answer the question “What are the similarities between recipes based on their ingredients?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dataset included 2,175 ingredients and each ingredient was treated as a categorical feature. Given the features’ data type, one-hot encoding was used in vectorization. The recipes underwent feature reduction using principal component analysis (PCA) at 80% explained variance. Assuming no prior knowledge on the recipes, the researchers analyzed the natural clusters of recipes through K-means since this method is intuitive and computationally efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the internal validation criteria, six (6) seemed to be the optimal number of clusters. Notably, this study revealed that recipes clustered based on broad flavor profiles (Pungent, Sweet, Savory, Hearty, Simple) and on the number of ingredients used (Easy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The generated clusters here can be used as an alternate classification system that is more based on flavor profiles as opposed to using ingredients and cuisine to group recipes together. Classification via flavor profiles may provide a novel and more intuitive method of catering to the tastes of customers. Moreover, results of this study can serve as an input to a food recommender system and as a cornerstone for future food anthropologic studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;note&quot;&gt;Note:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To see the files and codes used for this project, click &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ongchelseaanne/Classifying-Food-Images-using-Deep-Learning&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For questions and inquiries, you may send me a message via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ongchelseaanne&quot;&gt;Linked in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/clustering-recipes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/clustering-recipes/</guid>
        
        <category>food</category>
        
        <category>recipes</category>
        
        <category>ingredients</category>
        
        <category>cooking</category>
        
        
        <category>Data Mining and Wrangling</category>
        
        <category>Web Scraping</category>
        
        <category>Clustering</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Personalized Recommendation System using Collaborative Filtering of Zomato Restaurant Reviews</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subject/s of Focus: Big Data and Cloud Computing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authors: James Labergas, Chelsea Ong, Lance Sy, Maisie Tan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My team developed a collaborative-based recommender system via Alternating Least Squares and a content-based recommender system using restaurant reviews scraped from the Zomato website. The recommendations generated can be used by restaurant owners and customers in maximizing the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is very memorable for me because I presented for the first time in public. It was nerve wracking but overall it was fulfilling.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/BDCC_Presentation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BDCC Presentation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This project is for the fulfillment of the requirements in our Big Data and Cloud Computing course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Launched in India back in 2008, Zomato operates with the vision of bringing better food to people. To date, it is one of the largest food aggregators with operations spanning across 24 countries. With the millions of users on its platform and the customer feedbacks available in their page, there is no doubt that the platform has a rich understanding on its customers’ respective food profiles. With the objective of generating more value for the customers and other Zomate stakeholders, this project aims to address this question, &lt;strong&gt;Can we develop a personalized restaurant recommender system for Zomato users?&lt;/strong&gt;. Using restaurant reviews data scraped from the Zomato website, we develop a collaborative-based recommender system via Alternating Least Squares, as well as a content-based recommender system. With these newly developed recommender systems, we then make recommendations to restaurant owners and customers to maximize the Zomato platform in understanding their customers more and to gain more traction for their food service establishments. We also propose for future researchers to include more filtering options and introduce more countries into the study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;note&quot;&gt;Note:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the files and codes used for this project, you may send me a message via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ongchelseaanne&quot;&gt;Linked in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/zomato-recommender-system/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/zomato-recommender-system/</guid>
        
        <category>restaurant</category>
        
        <category>zomato</category>
        
        <category>food</category>
        
        <category>spark</category>
        
        
        <category>Big Data</category>
        
        <category>Recommender System</category>
        
        <category>Cloud Computing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Uncovering Cuisines Based on Ingredients</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subject/s of Focus: Machine Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author: Chelsea Anne S. Ong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;executive-summary&quot;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way a nation distinguishes itself is through its geographical and cultural ties which includes local foods and ingredients. Because of these, some ingredients are strongly associated with a particular cuisine. For example, sushi is automatically categorized as japanese cuisine. Classification is easy for common dishes, but not for the not-so-common ones. Using lists of ingredients, the machine learning model is able to predict the correct cuisines 66.5% using L2 Linear Support Vector Machines (Linear SVM) with C=0.1. &lt;strong&gt;Chinese Cuisine turned out the be the easiest to predict&lt;/strong&gt; and Southern US the hardest. On the other hand, misclassifications occur mostly in British Cuisines which are predicted as Irish or Russian cuisines and Thai cuisines are predicted as Vietnamese cuisines. As a restaurateur or a chef, cuisine classification is important to establish their niche or delve into fusion cuisines. In addition, they can optimize their ingredients to avoid spoilage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I cook or eat, what comes to mind is what I find myself craving whether Japanese, Chinese, or Filipino food. After I decided on a cuisine, that’s when I decide on what specific food on that cuisine I would choose. What makes a dish aside from how it is prepared are its ingredients. How does the list of ingredients dictate the dish’s cuisine?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the data gathered from the kaggle competition “What cooking?”, which contains the list of ingredients for each dish, the target would be the cuisine (e.g. Chinese, American, Filipino). The dataset contains 39774 dishes from 20 cuisines. By virtue of machine learning, various machine learning classification algorithms shall be implemented and compare their accuracies. The main objective is to figure out what algorithm will have the highest accuracy and how accurate it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This project is for the fulfillment of the requirements in our Machine Learning course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;note&quot;&gt;Note:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To see the files and codes used for this project, click &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ongchelseaanne/Uncovering-Cuisines-Based-on-Ingredients&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, you may send me a message via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ongchelseaanne&quot;&gt;Linked in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- #### So how do we do spoilers?

```html
&lt;span class=&quot;spoiler&quot;&gt;My hidden paragraph here.&lt;/span&gt;
``` --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/uncovering-cuisines-ingredients/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/uncovering-cuisines-ingredients/</guid>
        
        <category>food</category>
        
        <category>ingredients</category>
        
        <category>cooking</category>
        
        
        <category>Machine Learning</category>
        
        <category>Multi-Class Classification</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Classifying Food Images using Deep Learning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subject/s of Focus: Deep Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author: Chelsea Anne S. Ong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This project is for the fulfillment of the requirements in our Deep Learning course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;executive-summary&quot;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A certain image does not only necessarily represent a single attribute and most of the time it represents more than two. In other words, there can be multiple titles or labels that can be given for a single image. This problem is called multi-label classification which is used for content retrieval and scene understanding among few. For this study, a multi label classification algorithm is applied on food images using Keras (with Tensorflow backend). A simple CNN model is altered to give way to multi label classification. To make things easier, pre-trained CNN models are used particularly ResNet50, MobileNet, DenseNet121, and Xception. Afterwards, comparison of these results shall be done with Nanonets Multi Label Classification API. The results show a better F1 score at &lt;strong&gt;75.06%&lt;/strong&gt; for Nanonets and only about &lt;strong&gt;70.46%&lt;/strong&gt; for Xception model. Both of these models can be used for deployment as they both display intuitive and sound results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we see certain food images, are they easy to describe? Sometimes yes, sometimes no. Because of this, I want to explore if Deep Learning can help me with classifying food images. Using the sample food images data gathered from the blog “How To Easily Classify Food Using Deep Learning and Tensorflow”, I shall run pre-trained CNN models to predict labels for a particular food image. Given a food item, I would like to know what are the possible labels for a certain food image. For instance, given an image of a beef, the model shall provide tag such as “meat”, “protein”. This model can be useful for content based retrieval for businesses especially for the food industry where automated dietary plan app can be made based on user requirements. The use of this model comes in by automatically retrieving relevant images for the specific food item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-application&quot;&gt;Web Application&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make things more interesting and cool, this project is also deployed using Flask. This is how the landing page look like.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Website_Front.png&quot; alt=&quot;Website Front&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dataset used and the model features are listed here.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Website_Desc.png&quot; alt=&quot;Website Desc&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For simplicity and faster running time, MobileNet model is used instead.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Website_Features.png&quot; alt=&quot;Website Features&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To demonstrate prediction of food tags, simply upload an image and the prediction will come out. In this example, the model tagged the food image of a pizza as mains, carbs, and fats. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Website_Demo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Website Demo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;note&quot;&gt;Note:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To see the files and codes used for this project, click &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ongchelseaanne/Classifying-Food-Images-using-Deep-Learning&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For questions and inquiries, you may send me a message via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ongchelseaanne&quot;&gt;Linked in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- #### How to use?

It's actually really simple! Add the rating in your YAML front matter. It also supports halfs: --&gt;

&lt;!-- ```html
---
layout: post
title:  &quot;Inception Movie&quot;
author: john
categories: [ Jekyll, tutorial ]
tags: [red, yellow]
image: assets/images/11.jpg
description: &quot;My review of Inception movie. Actors, directing and more.&quot;
rating: 4.5
---
``` --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/classifying-food-images/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/classifying-food-images/</guid>
        
        <category>food</category>
        
        <category>images</category>
        
        <category>tensorflow</category>
        
        <category>keras</category>
        
        
        <category>Deep Learning</category>
        
        <category>CNN</category>
        
        <category>Web Application</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
